That's so interesting. And there's so
much CSS stuff that I really
want to explore. I feel like there's a
lot of like a whole it's like it it's
own HTML almost. You know, it's like
it's
many things that
Like just how HTML has its has its own
little set of quirks, right? Like all
these like just like the thing we talked
about at the beginning with like target
and like being able to post to an
iframe. It's like this whole separate
it's got it all its own
uh you know, content
directives and everything. It's so
weird.
Words of wisdom from Joel.
It's CSS. It's like it's own HTML.
Yo, yo, yo. What's up, dude?
Yo, how's it going? Pretty good. You're
in the new house, I see.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir. In the new office.
I got barely any lights, but out of the
dungeon, yeah.
Sweet, dude. Sweet. Well, it has been a
while since we've covered any news or
anything like that. So, I'm thinking So,
here's what I'm thinking for today. I'm
thinking we're going to hit some some
cool new stuff that I've seen around.
I want to talk about the PortSwigger
nominations list, which you know, cuz we
talked about last week
or the week before depending on when
this
episode airs
about the top 10 web hacking techniques
and those are great, but there's also a
massive nominations list, which is just
really good quality research. So, we're
going to talk about that. And then I'm
going to drop some some report knowledge
and some CSS injection wisdom that I've
been working on for the past couple
weeks.
Awesome. Awesome. Yeah, dude, I saw that
you put a couple things in here that are
really interesting that I didn't know
about. So, I'm pretty excited to talk
a ton of stuff about CSS over the past
couple weeks, which is which has been
really fun.
Yeah, yeah. I've I've noticed I mean,
even some non-CSS things in here. So,
I'll let you Why don't you go ahead and
kick it off?
We'll we'll we'll we'll kick it off with
the cool HTML [__] first. That's the
name of the the heading in our document.
Um
Okay. So, I two things here, okay? So,
one of them is from Twitter from a guy
named J Kubic and and from another guy
named encode.art. And essentially,
what's going on here is people are just
kind of talking about
weird functionality in HTML. Um the
first guy encode.art
said, "Hey, did you know that the form
attribute on an input element can be
used to emulate nested forms or place it
outside of a form, but still be posted
with it?" And I think this is like
I don't know.
It's stuff like this I think a lot of
people don't share because it's not like
directly impactful to a vulnerability,
but also, you know, you we spend so much
time looking at HTML and CSS and JS. And
I just want to know everything about
that. So, I just wanted to call this out
as one of those one of those cool
quirks. And what exactly he meant by
that was, you know, you can have a form,
right? And if you put an input inside
that form, it gets automatically
included when that form is submitted.
But also, you can have an input outside
of that form. So, not inside the nested
form tag. And if you have the form
attribute on that correlating it to the
ID on the actual form itself, then it
will also be submitted with the form.
So, I think that that's that's a pretty
cool way to smuggle data into a form
submission if you have some sort of HTML
injection or something like that.
Yeah, what this reminds me of is um
you can do this with labels, right?
There's like a label element or
something. And I think that's the most
common place I've seen this where it
like references the name of another
element like
target type thing.
Right? But I'm not sure it's like used
in a meaningful way with labels where
this seems to be significantly um
I mean, it's it's super weird that you
can just set the target to a specific
iframe for a form that's outside that
iframe and have it submit to that
iframe. Yeah, so the four Okay,
interesting. So, for the label one, it's
the it's the four. Oh, so that's the one
above it, right? So, so check
Click on the doc Click on the link in
the doc and then check the the sub tweet
of that. That's the one I'm talking
about the encode.art one here. I'll just
I'll drop it in the thing.
Yeah, yeah. Into the thing right there.
But the one above that is also really
cool, too. The one from um
the one from J Kubic. And that is one
that I was aware of, which is
you can use a target on a form to post
an iframe instead of the page. Um is is
what he actually said.
And I and I think that's that's one of
the more classic well-known examples.
And and I think Tom was saying like,
"Yeah, this is how we used to do sort of
before Ajax was around or before like
you know, XML HTTP request was around.
That's how we used to send requests
without refreshing the page, which is
kind of crazy
that he remembers that."
Back in the good old days. Seriously,
man. So, there's a bunch of cool stuff
with this. And I didn't actually put it
in the doc, Joel,
but it this reminds me of that now.
We'll we'll link those tweets, by the
way, down in the in the description.
Reminds me of something really really
rad I I did this week. Um
Okay. It This is in a bug that I I was
able um
Is this the second link?
No, this is not the second link. This is
This is This is something different. So,
I've also got that one. Did you You've
always got lots of fun stuff to share
this week.
Yeah, yeah. You got all sorts of
goodies.
So, there was a
So, there was a page that I needed to
uh clickjack a button
to get a user to log into
a a page and then I could exfil data
from that page using postMessage, okay?
And but but the problem was the user
wasn't being logged in
automatically. It was only something
they kept in the JS state. It wasn't
even in local storage or anything like
that. So, if you refresh the page, you
know, they were locked out.
Um So, here's here's how it it happened.
The user clicks a link
or clicks a button on the page, right?
Which I could clickjack cuz it was
frameable.
And then it opens up in another tab
um the
authorization flow for that page, right?
And then and then from that page,
you know, it would the user would be
automatically logged in and then the
original page that opened up would reach
into that frame, grab the authorization
header, log the user in, right? Um Okay.
And so, what I noticed was when it was
doing window.open, it was actually
pointing the name of the target frame
uh to a a frame with a name on it,
right? So, what I did is I framed two
frames.
This is this is this is getting kind of
crazy. I I framed two frames into my
page, okay? One of them was the page
that I wanted to do the iframe hijacking
from, right? And the other one was
just a bit page on the same origin as
the one that I was attacking. Um but had
the name the user one was doing in
window.open, right? So, when it did
window.open, it would open into that
iframe, right? Because it's same origin,
so it has the
the name is the same, so it has the same
reference. Then I could redirect that
page
that page's location and affect what the
original tab thought it was happening in
that page.
And then it was looking for a specific
hash. It would read that hash and do
stuff with it that allowed me to do
postMessage [__] Um Super interesting.
Yeah.
Does that make any sense or or is that
too complicated to explain in a podcast?
So, so the iframe with the name I
understand
99% of it. The iframe with the name that
was being reused. The first time you
opened it, it was in a different tab.
So, no. These are both iframed into my
attacker-controlled page.
Okay?
Okay, yeah. Yeah, and then it's using
the name as a reference, yeah. Exactly.
iframe and the name equals, you know,
login frame or something.
you can with named named tabs and stuff.
Exactly. And then it when it would did a
window.open into a frame called login
tab or whatever, right? It would
actually change that other iframe, but I
actually control that iframe because I
put the iframe source you know, I can
set the iframe source as the the parent
of that iframe. And so, I was able to
actually inject my attacker-controlled
content in there, which allowed me to
get access to some some postMessage
stuff. That's really interesting. I
wonder if there's other elements I Well,
for And for example, like I wonder if
you do a form post with a target as a
tab, a named tab, not a named iframe, if
it does the same thing.
Yeah, so I I think there's a whole a
whole like
I think opening doing window.open into a
specific named tab is kind of an
interesting Yeah, is an interesting
thing because I think in this scenario
I was essentially able to do
frame hijacking of sorts, right?
I was able to control what that iframe
was reading, you know,
from. And And I think that's an
interesting way to get injection there.
And I'm not sure what other use cases
they have besides for this sort of like
weird semi-login CSRF
you know, clickjacking postMessage [__]
that I did in this in this past example.
But I think it's
it was pretty interesting to note that
um that that was possible for one, that
you can have two iframes and force it to
open up into the other iframe. And then
and then for for two, that that other
iframe had to be same origin, which
makes sense.
But
just naming it the the like login frame
or whatever didn't do it. It had to be
login frame and the origin had to be the
same.
It is so interesting that, you know, cuz
that behavior as far as I was aware was
only for named like window targets.
And I didn't know that iframes counted
under that. So, now it makes me wonder
if there's other like HTML clobbering
type things that you other elements with
other names that you could use as other
targets
in the same way. It It that is
interesting though. Like I wonder Yeah,
if you could
quite clo- clobbering, but you know what
I mean? We're you know, creating
elements with names so that it's it's
using like a reference that's that the
element is not there. It wasn't
intending to actually Yeah, exactly. It
was expecting it to be a new a new
frame, but actually it's a it's a frame
that exists and you know, maybe in a in
an iframe context as well, you know,
something you can abuse maybe security
mechanisms surrounding iframes to make
that request fail and trigger some
unexpected behavior. Kind of
interesting.
Yeah, super interesting.
Yeah. So, anyway, that was fun. I I I
was glad that that worked out and I was
actually able to use that cool that cool
new technique. Um
but yeah, I've I've been cooking up some
other things in the iframe arena that
I'll I'll try to share as well once I
once I get some more research into them.
Yeah, man. So, okay. So, talking about
some some some what you've been cooking
up. All right. I saw this link that you
posted and uh while I was reading
through the doc.
And this is super interesting cuz I had
no idea this was a thing.
That's weird, right? The input thing?
Yeah, it it it's super interesting. So,
you put this link in here
and if you click it uh it's a link to I
assume this page just like
POC page, yeah. And yeah, so your POC
page for testing and it just basically
injects all the parameters that you put
in. But, the important part is there's
an input element here with a type of
image and a source element and it tries
to load it as an image.
I've I've never seen that before.
part of a It's like a form element, but
it's not even in a form. It's just like
in the body and it still does it. Yeah,
I I I don't know. Maybe this is just
something I've been sleeping on, but
somebody posted about this in the
in the
critical thinking discord and I was
like, "What the heck?" And the there's
an input tag and essentially it
functions as an image
if you have type equals image. And and
so, you know, what what what we just put
in the example there was input tag type
equals image source equals slash and it
just does like a
you know, image missing box It's like
broken image. Yeah, and and I was like,
"Okay, wow. This is really interesting."
especially in the context of which you
have sort of attribute injection and you
need some error handlers to trigger that
aren't triggering or something like
that. It may be possible for you to
redefine that input as an image and then
use some of the image associated error
handlers.
And so, I don't know. I haven't gone
through the full the full steps to say
like, "Hey, you know, does on error
trigger or whatever?" something like
that when the when the source tag
doesn't when the source doesn't actually
load up properly, but either way this is
a cool HTML quirk that I kind of wanted
to highlight. And I also want to just
tell the community like, "Please, if you
find out weird [__] like this, please
just drop it in the CTBB discord or like
put it on Twitter and tag me in it or
something like that because this is the
kind of stuff we love to talk about and
give publicity to and it strengthens
everyone's knowledge of HTML, which is
just a win for the community."
Yeah, so I'm reading through the docs on
this. You you've nerd sniped me, but
it says that this is this is used like
the intended purpose is to create
graphical submit buttons so the user can
click an image that is like a login
button or something instead of having to
style it purely with CSS. Yeah.
And it doesn't accept a value attribute.
It does
it the image goes in the source
attribute obviously.
Um
In addition to all attributes shared by
input elements, image button inputs
support the following attributes and
then they have a list of things. I just
tried it real quick, Joel. I just tried
it actually does trigger the on error
handler.
Which is kind of interesting, right?
Like I didn't I didn't I never really
thought on error could be triggered with
an input
uh tag. But, if you use it
For what it's worth, that's not
mentioned in the MDN docs.
Yeah, and and I'm looking at it right
here. It says the description for on
error is the on error event is triggered
if an error occurs when loading an
external file when used on audio/video
media related to events that occur when
there's some sort of disturbance when
the the media is loading. And so, this
is actually really interesting because
you might be in a scenario for example,
I was actually in a scenario recently
where on error was working as one of the
error handlers
and
it was getting past the WAF, but we we
couldn't get it to trigger on the
element that we were working with. So,
this is a great way to actually get on
error to handle or to trigger on an
input tag rather than on an image tag.
Interesting. The other interesting it
says here is that when the user
interacts with the image, the input is
handled like any other button input.
So, I'm wondering if you could use all
the other button handlers as well like
on click and everything as as well.
I'm sure you could cuz I think you can
do Can you Can you apply like an on
click even to
a
like
just a normal image?
even says the input type image element
is a replaced element, an element whose
contact content isn't generated or
directly managed by the CSS layer,
behaving much in the same way as a
regular image element IMG, but with the
capabilities of a submit button. Yeah,
it's it's pretty cool. You can do on
click, but you can also just do on click
on an image on an actual image, but the
the cool thing that I think happens here
is on error actually gets triggered,
which is something that's kind of
unexpected.
Yeah, and it's a whole different
element. You know, I think probably most
WAFs would not see an input element type
as some sort of XSS vector. Yeah. Super
super interesting.
indeed.
So, anyway,
critical thinking community, send us
your cool HTML [__] and we might talk
about it on the podcast.
Um all right.
What's up next? Let's see here.
Uh we got Alex Chapman
did his weekly update for his 2024 bug
bounty year-to-date journey, week eight.
Yeah, dude. I I've been So, I put this
one in there and I put the the other one
from
Monkey Hacks Kieran
on here because I think I just wanted to
shout this out.
So, Alex Chapman and Monkey are doing
some pretty awesome updates every week
on their bug bounty hunting experience
or I think monthly for Yeah, for Kieran.
Um Yeah.
And I think these are really cool to
keep an eye on to see how other hackers
are doing and also just kind of know
that other hackers get duplicates and
informatives and that sort of thing.
And I think Kieran actually does a
little bit more in-depth analysis of
of his being like how many hours this
week he hacked
how many hours he's got left in his
challenge, how many bugs got triaged,
how much money, you know, transparently
he's making. So, I think I think these
are both really good trends from the
community and you can kind of see the
development of hackers as they grow when
they're writing up these sort of things.
Yeah, for sure. I So, I've been also
tracking my
stats like actually
both like money-wise just like as a
whole just for bounties and then also
daily
um what targets I'm looking at, how much
time I'm spending
I I was about to say something that was
going to get me canceled. I I'm I'm
laughing because I'm thinking about this
chat that you and I have with Naggly and
how much freaking money Naggly's making.
Like
I don't even want to look at his time.
It's going to make me sad. Yeah, cuz cuz
he's like, you know, we set up something
where it's like, you know, we can sort
of
you know, have transparency and hold
each other accountable for bug bounty
stuff and Naggly's just in there like
popping bugs all the freaking day.
Like 90% of these entries for what he
was looking at just says wandering
around some some programs.
Just wandering around then it's just
like
bounty bounty bounty bounty like six
paid three paid It's It's crazy. So,
yeah. I I'm I definitely have a lot more
gaps in mine
and a lot less bounties and a lot less
reports,
but I think it's actually really nice to
be able to track it in this way
cuz it helps me sort of see like
what I'm
where I'm spending time, what things are
working, what things aren't and it also
kind of forces me to accept like the
some of the realities of like full-time
hunting. Like I'm very fail- failure
averse. So, when I hack like
I can probably count on two hands the
number of dupes I have.
And so, like I very much would try to
avoid that type of stuff, but when
you're like pushing to hack every single
day or hack like on a very very regular
basis, these things just happen.
Um and they're unavoidable. And so, it
kind of forces you to to come to terms
with that and deal with it a little bit
better. Absolutely. I I have to say,
dude, it's kind of impressive that
you've made it as far as you have in
hacking, you know, with a
with still a failure averse personality
because I feel like bug bounty and
hacking in general is just nothing but
failure. Like you're just failing
constantly. You're just like constant
stream of failure.
That's probably the biggest thing that
I've really really picked up as I've
gone is like, "Oh, yeah. This is a like
95%
fail and 5% win."
If you're very good. If you're getting a
95% fail rate in hacking, you rock. You
know. Yeah, yeah. You did it. You made
it. No, that that that is interesting.
Do you How do you I mean, I know that's
been a little bit tough on you in the
past as well of like, you know, just
when you're on sort of a down streak or
whatever that that'll get in get in your
head or whatever as it does for
everyone. What do you mean in the past?
You know,
or or presently. Um but
you know, it's something you just got to
push through. It's something that makes
you more of a long-term hacker rather
than someone who just dabbles into bug
bounty.
If you want to actually be a bug bounty
hunter for a long-term, you've got to
figure out how to push through these
mental ups and downs. And and just like
we talked about on the gadget episode,
having things like finding gadgets and
logging gadgets as a sense of motivation
really important to keep you going even
in the face of failure.
Yeah, for sure. Like we we were working
on something last week that was so close
to a really cool bug. It's like it's
still like
It's like so frustrating and I came back
to it like the day after and like, you
know, we we again we got it even closer,
but it's now at a point where I don't
think it's possible to
escalate it and it's so So wait, okay,
so let's talk about that a little bit.
Why is that authorization header getting
stripped out?
So, it's getting stripped out Give them
context a little bit, too.
Sure. Yeah, I mean I can leak this, I
guess. I don't know. It doesn't matter.
So, there's
there's a web view in an app. We'll say
it like that.
Where you can
the activity is exposed
and it has URL handlers set up so that
when you click a link to this domain, it
opens that that domain in a web view
and it makes a back-end API request
through OKHTTP. So, what it's designed
to do is it's designed to activate a
certain feature. You click this link, it
turns it on in the app and it sends a
little, you know, this setting's been
turned on or whatever.
Um
and it takes that URL when it's
comparing like when it should make the
request, it looks for a specific string
within there. It just checks if that
exists anywhere within the URL instead
of checking that it's exactly that path.
And if it is, then it sends it like an
HTTP request like an API request. If
it's not, then it just opens it in
right. And and if it's not, it just
opens it in your browser like it would,
you know, any other links.
Ideally, it wouldn't be exploitable, but
obviously there's a bypass here where
you you know, you just put like a URL
parameter with that name and it will
send it like an to to an arbitrary
attacker controlled URL. So, what you've
got is you can craft a link that has a
specific path in it in a query parameter
and a hash or something like that. And
if the specific string is in there, then
it will send a request including
you know, the authorization header and
some of these other important parameters
to that that path. Is that right?
Right. Now, the big caveat here is that
the way that it's set up is that it's
registered with the HTTPS scheme and a
domain name as the
as the host, right? So, it means that
the URL that you're sending it to has to
be within the root domain of this host
that we're attacking, right? So, you
can't just be like attacker.com with
that parameter because that won't work.
It won't even pass the Android manifest
verification because the intent filters
are in the Android manifest. Okay. It
has to be like matching the host and
then it does something. So, I reached
out to you. I was like, "Hey, I have
this really interesting thing.
Um do you happen to have an open
redirect?"
Yeah, boy, that open redirect vendor.
Your boy.
like, "Yeah, actually actually we do. We
have some gadgets." And so,
you were like, "Does it can it be HTTP
or does it have to be HTTPS?" I was
like, "I I don't know, honestly."
So, we tested it and at first it did
nothing and I was like, "Well, that's
mega frustrating. Looks like it won't
work." And you're like, "Well, maybe
just like test it if it does HTTPS." And
I was like, "Okay,
yeah, I'll take a look." And then
it wasn't following redirects, right?
That was what it was? Yeah, initially it
wasn't doing anything. So, like we sent
it I could see it it like hitting the
target URL that we had specified and it
would be sent like back a 302, but then
nothing would happen. And so, I was
like, "Okay, well, this is kind of
shitty, but
you know, I guess that is what it is.
I'll just note this down."
following redirects, but actually it is
following redirects. Actually, it is.
Right. And you're like, "Hey, like just
following up like did you test and see
if that works on HTTPS?" And I was like,
"Let me test it." And so, I go and I
test it and I set up a match and replace
to set it to HTTPS and like attacker
controlled domain and sure enough it
works. And not only that, it's actually
sending custom headers. So, I was like,
"Oh, for sure this is account takeover."
But when I looked closer,
for for context it's account takeover
because the the off is all through an
authorization bearer header.
So,
my assumption was that it was being sent
because it was sending all these other
custom headers.
Problem is it sends all these custom
headers to our target domain, but not
the authorization header. And I was
like, "Why is it not Why is it doing
that? There must be a check somewhere."
I'm digging I'm digging I'm digging. I
don't find an off check. I don't find a
domain check. I'm like, "What the heck
is going on here?"
I go and I start reading the code for
OKHTTP, right? for OKHTTP, which is
making the API request. And as it turns
out, OKHTTP has a specific check where
when you are making a request, it will
try and reuse connections and
in the process of doing that, it checks
if it can reuse a connection by if the
scheme is the same, the host is the same
and the port is the same. So, when we
send our our our redirect back and it
follows the redirect, it checks, "Oh, is
this going to the same host and port and
scheme?" If not, explicitly strip out
the authorization header.
So annoying, dude. Cuz all the other
headers were passed through, too, but
not the authorization. If they were
using anything this except for
authorization, you know, like
X-Authorization or like, you know,
site.com-authorization
or something like that, then it would
have been fine, but the authorization
header
Exactly. So, that's another gadget.
We'll put that one in the notes and, you
know, maybe it'll come in use
at some point. But yeah, it's so
frustrating cuz, you know, it's right
there like the all the custom headers
that are sent are sent to the redirected
URL except for this one because it's
explicitly pulled out by OKHTTP.
a bunch of like signing headers, too.
So, there's not like a bunch of no like
PII or anything like that is sent along
with that header even if the user's
logged in, unfortunately.
No, it's just for like request
authorization, basically. Like to, you
know, stop fraud or something. I don't
know. Sucks, dude. Well, we'll have to
see. So, essentially in order for us to
exploit the specific gadget in the way
we originally hoped, we would need to
find some sort of disagreement between
the Android intent
parsing, you know, the domain parsing in
that and OKHTTP as far as the,
you know, deciding what domain is being
used. Is that accurate?
Yeah, potentially. Maybe
one other thing we could look at is
maybe there's some sort of handoff where
it transfers the cookie into or sorry,
the off header into a cookie off because
I've seen that before where, you know,
it'll take the mobile off that's
typically through a bearer token or
something like that and then it
it sends a request that then turns those
into cookies which it then uses to like
open a web view so that you're logged in
in your browser or something like that
automatically. Um and it might be able
to function that way if we could control
the flow. But yeah, it's it's it's like
unfortunately it's like right there, but
it's like it's right it's so close that
I'm almost tempted to like report it
just but I don't think they would accept
it.
No, I don't think they would they they
would accept it, either. The the only
other thing I can think of is like,
"Hey, maybe there is some sort of
transformation that's happening on
specific types of characters between
when the domain name is parsed by the
intent filter and when it's actually
being used in OKHTTP." Like, you know,
maybe like a backslash is being
converted to a slash or something like
that. Something we could abuse to
actually get the actual host to redirect
the host that OKHTTP sends to us to
actually point towards our domain, but
yeah, I don't know, man. Well, we'll uh
I think there is, actually, for what
it's worth. I'm pretty sure it's
mentioned in Buggy Pros golden
URL techniques, but
the problem is that that takes the the
attack complexity and puts it at high,
right? And so, right now it's the user
clicks a link in their browser
and you get an ATO versus you need an
app on the phone to craft a specific
object that can then be sent in an
intent which then open and so, it the
yeah, it becomes a whole thing.
Yeah, that that's tricky. We'll have to
we'll have to come back to that. But
anyway, man, it it's good to it's good
to see, you know, you writing down those
those gadgets and still finding stuff.
And I know the the the failures, the the
things that are gadgets not bugs kind of
hit hard a little bit sometimes, but
very cool [__] either way.
Yeah, you know, let's actually talk
about this Yelp bug because it's very
similar, actually, in the in the sense
of sort of this all this like
redirection and tabs and all sorts of
cool stuff. This is a really really cool
report. You sent this to me. I had not
seen this.
When was this disclosed? It must have
been pretty recently, right?
Yeah, dude. I don't know. I guess
this this episode is going to air a
little bit later, so it's fine. But I
was kind of a little bit
skeptical to talk about this bug on the
pod cuz I feel like Yelp might be one of
those programs that everyone is sleeping
on. You know, like the bounties are
pretty freaking good for this program.
Look at it. It's like mediums are 1.5k
to 4k. Criticals are 7 to 10. You know,
like and and there there's like no
traffic on the program. Um so, I don't
know. Could be a could be a pretty good
one to look at. And so, I was kind of
looking through the the activity on this
one and came across this report and it
seems like they've got a bunch of
sketchy functionality built into this
this their architecture as well. So,
cool stuff there. Hey guys, real quick,
I want to remind you about the critical
thinking Discord community. There's been
a ton of great activity on the chats
lately. People just kind of shooting the
breeze to drop in new hacking tips and
advice,
sharing cool research, that sort of
thing. So, it's definitely something
you're going to want to get in on if you
haven't already. Also, we've got the
subscriber tiers in place now, which
will give you access to really cool
things like masterclass, AMA,
just random scripts that I drop. It's
kind of like our inner circle. So, if
you want to get in on that, please do.
We would really appreciate it. Also, it
helps support the show. So, if you're
interested in any of that, head over to
ctb.show/discord
to join the community today and we'll
see you over there. All right, back to
the show.
Yeah, this is a cool program.
One of my one of my old co-workers
worked at Yelp and it always seemed like
a pretty solid program. I want to I'm
trying to remember who it was. I swear I
know at least one person who was like a
really hardcore Yelp hacker. I'm trying
to remember who it was. Yeah, I don't
know. This report came out in July 2023,
so it's pretty recent. So they still
have a decent amount of traffic. I mean
like you know, this isn't some super old
report and stuff like that. They're
finding cool stuff on it in the past
year. So.
Yeah, it's really interesting
that
cuz cuz I scrolled down and saw when it
was disclosed and I mean it was only 6
months ago. So it's pretty cool
that that this report was disclosed.
Also, one really interesting thing I've
noticed
Okay, well why don't you tell them about
the report first? So how about that?
Yeah, okay. Hold on. Hold on. Hold on.
Did you notice that programs now it says
the bounties paid in the last 90 days is
a range? Oh, no. I didn't I didn't
notice that.
Is it for all programs?
I
the two I've looked at so far
Interesting. Why I wonder why they
switched to that.
I think I might know who caused that.
Oh, dude. What the heck? Oh, it's not
everything now.
no. I just checked I just I just checked
another one. It's actual number. So I
think I think it just depends on the
program.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Maybe it's by default
though. That's weird. I never noticed
that until now that there was ranges,
which is kind of interesting.
kind of interesting. Very cool. But uh
okay, anyways. Anyways, okay. So this
bug is so cool. Okay. Um so basically it
all started as a self-XSS. Okay? So when
you sign up
start. Yeah, as all as all good bugs do.
So when you sign up
and you create an account, you can put
an XSS payload in the part of the email
before the domain before the at symbol
and it will pop when you log in
basically, right? So by itself pretty
lame. However, there's this
functionality in Yelp, which you may
have noticed, which is that Yelp has a
lot of different localization and global
websites. So they have you know, yelp.
co.uk,
yelp.in, yelp.dk,
right? And so
with this functionality, there has to be
some sort of way to transfer your off
session across websites. So when you you
know, log in on yelp.com and you want to
go to yelp.dk
how does it log you in automatically?
So it has this thing called a cookie
bridge that they created.
So the way it works is that there's two
endpoints. There's the store endpoint
and the retrieve endpoint. So when you
hit the store endpoint on the cookie
bridge, it takes all your cookies, it
stores them and it gives you back a
unique token. And then when you use that
unique token and you send it to the
retrieve endpoint, it sets all your
cookies that were stored on the new
domain. So if you say, I want to store
all these cookies for the
DK locality, it says, "Okay, sounds
good. Here's your cookie retrieval
token." Then you retrieve all the
cookies on the .dk domain and it sets
all your cookies again so that you have
a session automatically automatically
logged in on DK, all good to go.
So you hit the  store endpoint
with the locality that you want and it
gives you it returns back
under the original domain
and and then it generates one-time use
token on the target domain that you can
use to retrieve your cookies and get
them set on that domain in your browser.
Correct. When you hit consume it or when
you hit retrieve it consumes that that
token and it sets the cookies
and then you're logged in on the new on
the new domain. So it shares the session
It must be the like the same back end
basically.
Super cool little gadget there.
Super interesting gadget, right? So
the hacker realized
the researcher little Indian they
realized, "Okay, well, if I have a
self-XSS here, I can basically force
force someone to log in using my
auto log you know, this cookie bridge
onto a different domain into my account,
which has an XSS and then I can pop in a
self-XSS in their user context instead.
So
they put together a POC. Obviously that
worked, but now how do you escalate it
further? Because like yeah, you have an
XSS in the victim context, but their off
is all within you know, HTTP-only
cookies, all that kind of stuff. So
what do you do? Well
cookie bombing is what you do, right? So
the researcher realized that if when you
set a bunch of cookies for this retrieve
endpoint, open resty will fail. If you
set these huge long cookies and cookie
bomb it, it just fails it fails to parse
and so it can't actually consume the
token. It's breaking at the web server
layer. It's not even hitting the
application behind it.
it doesn't it just like fails and that
cook that token that unique token to get
to retrieve all the cookies stays in the
URL. Okay? So
you have two tabs, right? The victim is
logged in on like .com. They open this
link and it hits the cookie bridge,
which then logs them into the victim or
sorry, the attacker account. Triggers
the self-XSS.
Right. So it auto logs you in onto the
new domain. Now on the old domain you're
still logged in. Right? On the new
domain, you're also logged in but into a
different account. Okay? So then
you
from the the the new account, the
attacker controlled account on on the
second tab that you have an XSS context
in
you cookie bomb to the retrieve endpoint
and you
send the other tab to store. So you
store the old cookies on .com and then
you cookie bomb it and then you send
them to the next domain, which should
automatically try and retrieve it with
your with your storage token or
whatever, the cookie retrieval token,
but because it's cookie bombed it fails
to consume the token. So now the
attacker has a controlled context on the
same origin
on on tab B and on tab A they have an
unclaimed cookie token that will give
them all of the victim's cookies for the
original you know, .com account and they
just pull that out and consume it and
it's full ATO.
Dude, nice. Okay. Okay. So
like sort of using the the cookie bridge
endpoint, we log in to the attacker's
account, right? Pop the self-XSS. Then
on the previous tag tab we relogged the
user into their own account using the
cookie bridge and then we
but when it actually tries to actually
consume that token to log them back in,
that that endpoint gets cookie bombed so
that that token never gets consumed. It
grabs the URL, exfiltrates it to the
attacker's attacker's account.
Yes. And the best part is that it's
super reliable because you can cookie
bomb specific paths, right? So they only
cookie bomb the retrieve path. So
you cookie bomb it, you send them to
store, that works fine. As soon as the
application tries to then retrieve it,
it fails because just that path on on
the same domain has been cookie bombed
and you can claim that cookie and you
can re-consume.
Heck yeah, dude. This is For any of you
guys that weren't that weren't following
that that explanation, you can find this
report in the description. We'll link it
to this episode. Also the attacker one
report 2089042.
So definitely go check this one out.
It's a great example of how to escalate
a self-XSS and also utilize some cool
bridging, which we talked about in in
the past as well, right? I think we
talked about it on the gadget episode.
Anytime there's some sort of
off transfer or data transfer between
top-level domains or even between
subdomains,
that is very interesting to look at it
at because doing that they have to
create some secure way to to you know,
go through same origin policy and and
browser level um
restrictions on off being shared across
domains and those those transitions are
always vulnerable to something. Yeah.
Yeah, I will say for self-XSS, probably
the two main ways that I've ever seen it
being exploited are through some sort of
auto login where you can force a victim
into your account that has the XSS
payload and then you do something from
there or you have an XSS payload that is
not being sanitized and then you just
roam around the website until it pops
somewhere. Yeah.
That's that's
Yeah.
Great summary there.
Yeah, pretty much. That's good, dude.
Okay, we got a we got a couple more
things here. I know you've got a a hard
stop coming up here shortly, but
um
let's let's sort of power through these
next two
three really quick and then I'll I'll
talk about some of the stuff that I've
been working on. Um so I just wanted to
do a shout out to a pretty cool piece of
I don't know. A a conglomerate of
information done by a guy named
0xdev_alias.
As I said, I tweeted it out a little
while back about how I think that
uh
parses for specific
like client-side
environments will become more more
popular.
Things like de- unpacking webpack and
and that sort of thing.
And this guy 0xdev_alias, who I think
we've mentioned on the pod before,
commented and listed a bunch of notes
and tools that they've put together for
doing just this.
So there's one gist that just gist gist
gist gist that
that contains just a ton of information.
Wait, what?
GitHub note to Exactly, right? I don't
even want to start the argument. We're
not even going to start that battle, but
there's one
gist that that has just a ton of
information.
So we'll drop that down below on like
what is this? 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 different
tools to
deobfuscate
or unminify obfuscated web app you know,
JS code. So definitely something to
check out there. I I glanced over it.
The one that looks really good
ironically is called wakare, which is a
Japanese word for understand. And I just
think that it reminded me of sort of a
interesting cultural experience I had
when I was in Japan because I was
creating a a JS monitoring tool actually
and I named it kanshi, which is monitor
in Japanese, right? Cuz I was like, "Oh,
this is cool. I'm like learning
Japanese, whatever." I'm just going to
name my cool my tool the the Japanese
word. And my Japanese friends were like,
"Did you actually just name this tool
monitor?"
It sounds so weird to that, right? In
the foreign language cuz it's like
I just named the tool monitor or
understand. And now I'm starting to
understand a little bit what they're
talking about as my language skill has
has increased a little bit. But there's
this tool Wakaru that is a JavaScript
decompiler.
Seems to support
webpack and browserify.
So this seems really cool and they have
actually a live demo of it. Joel, I'm
not sure if you saw that. It's in the uh
uh Yeah, I'm looking at it right now.
This is really awesome. Yeah, you can
just paste the the data in there and it
just transforms it.
Yeah, this looks really cool. I want to
try this out with some more production
stuff. I feel like it's always kind of
hit or miss. You know, sometimes you you
throw something in there and it works
perfectly and other times you throw
something in there and it just has no
idea what to look at. And it it it only
works in specific cases. If this worked
sort of like generally, that'd be really
really awesome. I feel like I have a
bunch more tools to put in my arsenal
now. So I'm going to find some some good
examples and I'm going to I'm going to
maybe do a little
side-by-side test.
Yeah, that'd be really cool. I think
it'll be helpful and I know you know
when stuff is done in the browser like
this even with like big JSON, you know,
minification / beautification things,
the browser gets kind of slow. So I'm a
little bit apprehensive about that, but
um if it does work as well as it looks
like it works,
it could be really really helpful. And I
think there's just should be
Yeah. should be more stuff surrounding
the space. And because somebody
actually,
you know, kind of went through this
whole thing to deminify this stuff
de-obfuscate it, I think it would also
be pretty interesting to look at where
client-side paths are being defined in
those kind of frameworks
and try to extract those as well. In a
more reliable way than just let's you
try to hit, you know,
double quote slash and then take it you
know, write a regex to pull everything
after that. Um Yeah, for sure.
So this is mostly just a extra little
piece of research is is needed for this
for anyone who's listening that's
interested in that arena. We'll drop
those down in the in the description as
well.
Yeah, well well there's so much I mean
this
I don't I I don't even have a good way
to express how long this It's so long,
right? There's so much information here.
I mean, I can't I don't even know how
long it must have taken to compile this
thing.
if they used ChatGPT to actually like
summarize this or something because I
know so one of the things that and this
is the other thing I wanted to shout
out. So I'm glad glad that popped into
my mind was um
uh
o x dev alias also has this repo called
ChatGPT Source Watch and it's called and
the readme describes it as analyzing the
evolution of ChatGPT's codebase through
time with curated archives and scripts.
And I think this is a great example for
any of you that are interested in doing
um
I guess
application specific source code
monitoring. I think this could be a
really good example of what you could do
with that because it seems like they
have dev alias has put together
something here to that really analyzes
why they've been doing so much unpacking
research.
Yeah, so clearly.
And so this could be a great example to
kind of build your own structure off of.
And it seems like they have a lot of
lessons that they've learned.
Yeah, yeah, absolutely. Super cool. I'm
going to have to read through all these
and and look at all these tools. Yeah,
for sure. All right.
What what do we want? Okay. So I guess
I'll just mention let me just mention
these other
two things really quickly here, okay? Um
Just want to shout out some cool places
to find research after that top 10
place. So I was talking to Saroush I R S
D L
and they mentioned that Reddit
web security research could be a good
place to find some good some good um
uh
you know, research that should
potentially be popping up in the top 10
web hacking techniques stuff, you know.
So if you're looking for that sort of
high quality research, the stuff that
was getting posted in hashtag cool
research in the CTBB channel
or CTBB Discord, you might be able to
find it on Reddit at web security
research. Um
For those of you that
is cool.
There's a there's a bunch of articles in
here that I've there's like there's a
there's a path confusion on mod
security. It's pretty interesting. Yeah,
I I I need to go through all that.
By Albino Wax? It's not
it's not particularly like mega active,
I don't think, you know, but I No, but
there's a lot of familiar names in here
of people who are posting. Def Param,
Albino Wax. Albino Wax is the
administrator.
It's it's it's Albino Wax. So it's James
Kettle and Gareth Hayes are the two
admins of this sub in it. So
That's probably a good sign that there's
that there's decent research and Indeed.
So check that out.
Check out um
uh
the the the one that I
was a list of
I want to say it's under the media tab.
Yeah, it's under the media
.md file in that resource in that
resources for uh bug bounty hunter
beginners. It just lists a ton of people
to follow on Twitter that are correlated
with bug bounty stuff.
Um so definitely check that that boy
out. There should be a bunch of good
stuff in there.
Oh yeah, it's lib is media resources on
the on the table contents. Got it.
Yeah, there's that one and then
obviously
checking out the nominations as well for
the top 10 web hacking techniques of
2023 or for for any year, 2022, 2021,
etc.
Is also a great place to find good
research that maybe didn't necessarily
make the top 10, but is really high
quality stuff.
You know, I swear we just talked about a
bug from 2019 like a week or two ago,
right? So
These these things are coming up all the
time.
You know,
I think it's super valuable to go and
back and read some of that old research
cuz there's this whole recent bias
thing, right? Where like you read a
bunch of new research and then it's like
the only thing that you're looking for
and thinking about. And these other
things that are still very much so
there, but we're just at the top of your
mind like two years ago are no longer
there. And so like going back and just
refreshing yourself on these types of
techniques and stuff just bring make
them recent again, you know.
I think you'll find that if you start
hunting like you did three years ago,
you're still going to find the same
things.
Yeah, that's a great point. There
there's a lot of stuff that as you sort
of evolve as hacker, stuff kind of falls
off your radar. We were talking about
this with the blind XSS thing when when
Naham came on.
You know, I was looking for blind XSS
all the time a couple years ago and I
just didn't I just haven't been looking
for it as much lately until he kind of
reopened my eyes to it again.
So very very cool stuff to be found
there.
Yeah, absolutely. Okay, you want to talk
a little bit about CSS?
Yes. Okay, couple things. I'm going to
I'm going to talk about one report that
I submitted.
Um let me go ahead and open this bad boy
up.
Um
I'm going to talk about one report that
I that I submitted and and essentially
kind of take a little bit of a piece out
of that and um
apply it to a a sort of a bigger class
of vulnerabilities that I think
would be helpful to think about from
this perspective. So
the the vulnerability is this. It's it's
a way to leak information about a
password protected entity on the
website, okay? And essentially what it
takes advantage of is the fact that
when the owner goes to this page,
they don't see the password prompt,
right? It just takes them right into the
actual entity.
Whereas if anyone else goes to this this
link, they'll say, "Please enter the
password." And then you go right in. So
it's this concept of perspectives,
right?
And then you know, using some post
message related stuff, I was able to
leak the contents of that page back to
the attacker and
sort of leak something from behind
password password protected environment.
Um and I also was thinking about this in
a different environment on a different
bug,
a CSS injection related bug, okay? And
and here's here's what here's how that
one played out.
We got CSS injection.
And I was like, "Okay, I don't have
anything good to exfiltrate via
sequential import chaining on this
specific page, right? So how can I get
information onto this page so that I can
exfiltrate it with sequential import
chaining?"
Um
and the way that one of the ways that we
ended up being able to do that was
comment on the specific entity
a link to a specific URL that we didn't
have access to. But when someone who
comes to that page does have access to
that specific entity, then it creates
that little preview card. You know, you
know what I'm talking about? Like where
it's like, you know, here's a link and
it shows like the the image associated
with that you know, specific entity. And
also shows like the title
yeah, the the OG meta open graph stuff.
it did, right? You know,
but it was the way it was doing it in
this application, it was it was doing it
you know, within the same website. So
the person's cookies that were
associated with that certain page
navigation were being used and then they
would go and fetch that data. And for
me, that URL wouldn't look like
anything, but for the person who came to
that page that actually did have access
to that resource, it would populate the
name and the image associated with that
entity onto that onto that page, right?
So now we've been able to smuggle uh you
know,
some sensitive data into that page where
we have CSS injection and we can use
sequential import chaining to then
smuggle that information back out to the
attacker controlled server and gain
access to said resource via an
authorization token link that was a leak
that was being put into that actual
page.
That's so interesting. And there's so
much CSS stuff that I really
want to explore. I feel like there's a
lot of like a whole it's like its own
HTML almost, you know? It's like it's
There's so many things that
Like just how HTML has its has its own
little set of quirks, right? Like all
these like just like the thing we talked
about at the beginning with like target
and like being able to post to an
iframe. It's like this whole separate
it's got it all its own
you know content
directives and everything. It's so
weird.
Words of wisdom from Joel.
It's CSS. It's like its own HTML. It's
like its own HTML. Yeah, CSS for CSS.
gosh, dude. That's that's hilarious.
I do understand what you're saying
though. It you know, it's a fully it's a
very capable language. There's a lot of
really cool capabilities in it.
So, and I want to go talk about a couple
of those new ones um
uh in just a second.
And I think that they're probably making
a lot more changes to CSS core spec than
they are to HTML core spec.
They they they're certainly making a lot
of changes to CSS spec. Um
So,
one thing that I just kind of want to
leave the listener with there, think
about abusing perspectives in your
specific attacks and how you can
leverage the the victim's position
in the page, um you know, in the
application where they're authenticated
into the page and um
and use that to your advantage when when
uh bypassing you know, in in areas where
things are password protected and
they're not password protected for the
owner, which is a pretty common uh
mechanic in web apps that that share
information. Um
So, cool little tidbit there. Um
Yeah. Going off on what you were talking
about about how CSS has changed, there
was a new change to CSS recently. I want
to say late 2023 when it came out. Um of
this thing called container queries.
Have you seen that?
Container queries?
No, because I mean I really am not
up-to-date with CSS stuff. Like I think
I stopped learning about CSS when I
learned that it was so difficult to
center an element and I was like, "Okay,
web development's not for me." Yeah. So,
container I I definitely feel that. CSS
is absolutely frustrating to deal with.
Um
but I will say container queries are
pretty cool. And essentially what they
allow you to do is they allow you to
select
elements and affect elements
specifically based off of the size of
those elements.
And and there So, I think of it like
viewport
in in CSS but for specific containers.
So,
the
my idea with this and this is where
where I kind of went and I was talking
to Gareth about it for a little while.
And unfortunately it doesn't seem like
it's going to pan out, but my idea here
was if we could use CSS, you know, in
conjunction with all the sort of
traditional methods of for example
sequential input chaining and that sort
of thing
to leak the size of a container or the
size of a specific entity,
then we should be able to read arbitrary
data off of the page. Because what we
can do is we can apply a font
to with with different character sizes
for
or different widths of characters for
every single character
and then
adjust the size of um the container to
to include breakpoints
on specific characters. And if we can
leak the size of that container, then it
should tell us step by step by step by
step by step what the character is using
an Oracle based off of the width of that
container. So, I went down that whole
rabbit hole and unfortunately when you
apply when you define something as a
container using this stuff, it applies
some
attributes to it that won't allow it to
be fit to the
child element unfortunately.
So, it doesn't seem like it's going to
work with this, but it made me think,
"Hey, wouldn't it be really cool if we
put together a list of things? Like,
okay,
if we can leak the size of a container
that results in arbitrary character
read. If you can, you know,
isolate characters one by one
that blog post for like all the ways to
leak window references.
Exactly like that or You know
you know what
we're going to do this and
we're going to we're going to put it
right in the the critical fingers
discord.
gosh, dude. You're going to you're going
to give I'm going to have to get so nerd
sniped by this then. Dude, you'll
understand how much time I spent on this
specific thing already. Oh my gosh.
I'll help you with it. I'll help you
with it. Okay. It won't be like next
week, but we'll we'll try to have it out
by the end of the month I think.
Yeah. That that'd be really cool. I I
think it's really worthwhile doing. And
if we can and we should talk to Gareth
about it too cuz he's just like a wizard
with this sort of thing. But one of the
things that still remains sort of
unsolved um in the CSS world is like how
do we leak inner HTML? How do we leak
inner text, right? For a specific
element. Cuz if we could do that, then
we you know, provide a selector and it
would just give us inner text leaked to
our server, then CSS becomes a
totally different bug to to CSS
injection dots, right? Um
and so I think defining what some of
those goals might look like and breaking
it down into smaller sub problems could
be really helpful for the community. And
then when stuff comes out like, "Oh, CSS
container queries. Those allow you to
select based off of some things width.
Maybe we can use that to do XYZ." You
know, it becomes a lot more easier for
those you know, synapses to connect and
and to find cool cool connections. Yeah.
The other thing this reminds me of is
the exercise cheat sheet that
PortSwigger has. So,
perhaps we could even work with them
directly. So, yeah, we'll we'll we'll
keep you
you guys posted, but we'll we'll
definitely be releasing something into
the the CTBB critical fingers.
Yeah. That that'd be really rad. I I I
think I think that'll be that'll be
something that we can put together and
release that will have value and
increase sort of further the CSS
injection um
front so to speak. And I definitely want
to talk to Gareth about that cuz he's
got a bunch of expertise in that area.
Um Yeah, absolutely.
Speaking of that, I want to shout out a
specific repo um PortSwigger  CSS
exfiltration. This is something that
Gareth sort of pointed me to. It's 3
years old and I've never seen this repo.
Um and it's just a bunch of ways to
exfiltrate stuff via CSS. And some of
these are like the most wild thing I've
ever seen. Specifically, I want to
redirect you guys I want to I want to
point you guys to steal reversed
Firefox. And I'm actually going to go
ahead right now if it's still up. Let me
see if it's still up on my local host.
I'm going to actually show you guys a
demo of this for the for for those of
you that are on um
Yeah, it is. Okay, let me share my
screen really quick. For those of you
that are not are watching on YouTube, um
essentially what what's happening here
is
Okay, I'm going to refresh. There it is.
It's essentially applying keyframes to
transform a specific
length
of a of a container
of a div and it's saying, "Okay, I want
two characters to be in this in this
div. Three characters to be in this div.
Four characters to be in this div." And
then as it's doing that, it's using it
to sort of
a CSS selector for the first line of a
div to select specific
segments of that text and then applying
custom font to it to exfiltrate it out
to the attacker controlled server.
Um
This is so crazy. I'm like reading
through this and I'm trying to
understand how how this works and I'm
going to need to like
Yeah. It's not it's not a it's not a
quick glance
even for Joel.
is like this is cool. This is a
and you really you sniped me pretty hard
there.
Okay, I'll I'll I'll I'll let you I'll
let you get to all that.
Um but just wanted to shout that one
out. The other one that's really cool is
steal attribute values
checkboxes. I won't do a demo for that
one, but that one and then the steal
script contents. Any for anybody who's
interested in CSS injection, um those
three steal reversed Firefox, steal
script content, steal attribute values
checkboxes uh sort of sub directories of
the CSS exfiltration repo by PortSwigger
really awesome examples of the power of
CSS and what you can do with it.
Yeah, this is this is really really
cool. I have so many things to read.
This is so awesome. I know I know you
got a hard stop and I know you've got a
lot of things to read before you go to
your hard stop. So, Yeah, you just
exponentially grew my list of reading
items.
Sorry about that, man. But hey, you
know, what else is the pod for?
That's exactly right. That's exactly
right.
dude. Let's let's cut it there, yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, that's us.
That's the pod.